Gagandeep Singh Maken

Mumbai, Maharashtra, India



gagandsm@gmail.com



+91 7021258250 / +91 8805309999



linkedin.com/in/gagandsm

Summary

I am an aspiring leader with over 21 years of experience in Team management and building teams with expertise in New Business Development, Sales Process, Business Planning, Strategic Planning, Sales & Marketing, Market Research, Business-to-Business (B2B), Key Account Management, Channel Management, Large Enterprises and Government relationship management such as BFSI, Enterprise Accounts, Government & Defence Accounts and GeM.

I am driven to create and scale the best practices and systems for the organisation by identifying, creating and scaling the tools/programs for various segment oriented partners and customers.

Presently working with Fre8wise to develop long-lasting Strategical relationships with Enterprise and Government customers in Minerals & Mining, Manufacturing, Cement, Ports, Petrochemical, Automobile, Beverages, Fertilizers, FMCG and so on. To Promote our Quasi Blockchain & AI Based True-SaaS platform

Experience



Director Business & Strategy

Fre8wise

Jan 2022 - Present (3 months +)

Fre8wise is India's first Artificial Intelligence, Robotic Process Automation & Quasi Blockchain driven Digitally Connected Supply Chain Network.

Focusing on developing long-lasting Strategical relationships with Enterprise and Government customers as in Minerals & Mining, Manufacturing, Cement, Ports, Petrochemical, Automobile, Beverages, Fertilizers, FMCG and so on.

Helping the team build the future-ready SaaS platform focusing ease of work for the customers and helping them do predictive planning leading to a much simpler Supply Chain Management ecosystem.



💸 Sales Director – Partnership (West & South)

Skylo Technologies

Jun 2021 - Dec 2021 (7 months)

Primary Role to Develop Partnership across India in vertical of System Integration Partners/ Consultants/ Govt/ Enterprises/ OEM/ Agriculture/ Mining/ Fisheries to facilitate the subject specialist to grow the business by Solution Selling & Key Account Management.

- > Engaging specific customer segments and Partner networks.
- > Partnership onboarding and training, deal registration, SaaS or DaaS Module training, new product/ feature/Customer Segment awareness.
- > Ideated channel for different lines of business Marine, Mining, Government, Enterprise.
- > Customer presentation and engagement through partners.

- > Conducting Customer POC's along with the partners.
- ➤ Manage strategic alliances with Large SI.
- > Building Partner Program to keep the partners engaged and ensure higher revenue growth through them.



n Regional Manager Sales - West 1 (Feb-2007 to April-2021)

HP

May 2019 - Apr 2021 (2 years)

Managed a Team of 5 Sales Manager and Subject Specialist Across Maharashtra and Goa, along with a Team of 11 FOS's (Off role) for Distribution/Govt/Enterprises Sales.

Engaging directly with Key Accounts in Enterprise & Government customers such as TATA, Reliance, Aditya Birla, ICICI Bank, HDFC Bank, RBI, MAHAGENCO, NDA, HQ Southern Command, HQ Maintenance Command, WNC, MAHA IT, Tribal Dept. NPCIL, DAE and so on.



m GeM Specialist

HP

May 2018 - Apr 2019 (1 year)

Managed Relationship with GeM (Government e-Marketplace www.gem.gov.in) to Help HP Clean up the Catalog and Ensure Original HP Products are Sold on GeM.

Build an everlasting relationship with GeM as Key Account to ensure that the OEM Cartridge Catalog is Cleaned, where many unauthorized Sellers were selling NON-Original HP Consumable Products. We were able to do so with Team effort in Just 2 Months' time, where GeM Closed down the OEM Cartridge catalogue and replaced the same with OEM Cartridges/Consumable catalogue. This lead to a Business Growth of 190 Cr. In 10 Months and is continuing with Growth and beating all the Forecasts.

HP is the First company to have a Level 2 Dashboard on GeM.



Enterprise Specialist - West (Government & Defence)

HP

May 2014 - Apr 2018 (4 years)

Managing Defence & Government Business Maharashtra and Goa for HP's Consumable Range of Products.

KRA was to generate business from Defence and Government accounts by signing Rate Contract and ensuring the customer moves from alternate means of printing to buying of Original Consumables



n Area Sales Manager

HP

Feb 2007 - Apr 2014 (7 years 3 months)

Area Sales Manager – Rest of Maharashtra (May 2010 – June 2014)

>> Based out of Pune and managing ROM (Rest of Maharashtra) and Goa for HP's IPG Consumer business (HP Consumer Printers & Supplies) with total market size of 7.25 Cr for hardware Sale and 13.2 cr for aftermarket Sales (Supplies).

Area Sales Manager – Greater Punjab (Nov 2008 – April 2010)

> Managed Punjab + Himachal. For HP's IPG Consumer business (HP Consumer Printers) with total market size of 1 Cr pm.

Area Sales Manager – Rest of Karnataka (Feb 2007 – Oct 2008)

> Managed Karnataka Upcountry Market (ROK) + LFR + Retail Business for HP's IPG Consumer business (HP Consumer Printers) with total market size of 0.8 Cr pm.

Business Manager

WorldSpace

Jun 2006 - Jan 2007 (8 months)

> Responsible for handling Sales & Marketing operations across Bangalore.

Channel Manager

Tata Tele Business Services

Oct 2002 - May 2006 (3 years 8 months)

- > Involved in handling the distribution network for Post and Pre-Paid Sales across North / East Bangalore.
- > Ensuring timely payouts and ROI of the distributors.

Sales Manager

Agrochem Private Limited

Dec 1999 - Oct 2002 (2 years 11 months)

> Engaged in strategy planning for selling Pesticides across the rural market of Karnataka.

Founder

CyberWorld

May 1997 - Mar 2001 (3 years 11 months)

- > CyberWorld was the first customer to Payment Gateway PayPal and CCAvenue in India. We were the first e-commerce portal of India known as www.HolyBaba.com. Holy Baba was solely developed on ASP and MS Access Platform. Our Customer Base was mainly Europe and American Continent, selling Indian handcarts and Paintings online.
- > CyberWorld was also in web development projects for Indian and International Customers such as Avnet (China Wing), ChinaECNet.org, DwarikaPeeth.org, JyoteshPeeth.org.
- > CyberWorld was also part of tenting of various software such as Translation (English to German, French & Spanish), Voice Compression (Compression of WAV Files), SwarShala, Fruitloop.

Education



CCS (Chaudhary Charan Singh)University

2000, Bcom

1997 - 2000

Licenses & Certifications



Channel Management - Future Ready - Alliance School of Business

Issued Sep 2008 - Expires Dec 2008

Skills

Solution Selling • Business Alliances • Go-to-market Strategy • Sales Management • Competitive Analysis • Key Account Management • Change Management • Business Expansion • Strategic Partnerships • Business-to-Business (B2B)